Let the festivities begin.
Midsommar is a horror, drama, mystery film directed by Ari Aster.
Several friends travel to Sweden to study as anthropologists a summer festival that
is held every ninety years in the remote hometown of one of them.
What begins as a dream vacation in a place where the sun never sets, gradually turns into a dark nightmare as
the mysterious inhabitants invite them to participate in their disturbing festive activities.
Dani, played by Florence Pugh.
Christian, played by Jack Reynor.
Josh, played by William Jackson Harper.
Mark, played by Will Poulter.
Pelle, played by Vilhelm Blomgren.
Maja, played by Isabelle Grill.
Midsommar is a 2019 folk horror film written and directed by Ari Aster.
It stars Florence Pugh and Jack Reynor as an American couple who
are drawn into a violent cult in rural Sweden.
Supporting actors include William Jackson Harper, Vilhelm Blomgren,
Ellora Torchia, Archie Madekwe, and Will Poulter.
A co-production between the United States and Sweden, Midsommar was initially pitched
to Aster as a straightforward slasher film set among Swedish cultists.
While elements of the original concept remain in the final product, the finished film focuses on a
deteriorating relationship inspired by a difficult breakup experienced by Aster himself.
The film's soundtrack, composed by the British electronic musician
Bobby Krlic, takes inspiration from Nordic folk music.
The film was predominantly shot on location within the Budapest
metropolitan area of Hungary, from July to October 2018.
Midsommar was theatrically released in the United States by A24 on July
3, 2019, and in Sweden by Nordisk Film on July 10, 2019.
The film grossed $48 million and received positive reviews, with
praise for Aster's direction and Pugh's performance.
The film explores themes of loss of loved one, ritual, paranoia, sweden, cult.
The tone is dark and emotional and mind_bending.